Mohamad Rabbani

Electrical & Computer Engineer



mrabbani@outlook.com



+7 705 203 5486



mohamadrabbani

Profile

Motivated individual with a passion for software development aspiring to build innovative and cuttingedge business solutions for a refined user experience. Diligent Electrical & Computer Engineer with 8 years of experience in oil & gas mega projects and the skills to complete work in a well-organized and professional manner. Experienced in working with small and large teams of diverse backgrounds across multiple companies.

Relevant Skills

Courses

- Agile Scrum Methodologies
- Technical Program Management
- Software Testing

Technical Skills

- Java, C++
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- SQL
- Git, GitHub

Soft Skills

- Team Leadership & Supervision
- Effective Communication
- Prioritization
- Decision Making
- Time Management

Professional Experience

Mar 2020 – Jul 2023 E&I Engineer Consolidate Contractors Company

FPG 3rd Generation Plant, Republic of Kazakhstan

- Utilizing advanced work packaging principles to facilitate workplace management and reduce construction costs
- Performing early forecasting of work front and preparing material and tools for smooth flow of work
- Coordinating with disciplines (Work face planning, engineering, planning and productivity) and client representatives in addition to arranging logistics to request and deliver material to site
- Ensuring that the site is properly staffed to perform all material management duties including material receiving, storage, preservation, inventorying and issuing
- Identifying contractor responsibilities and scopes of supply, preparing material takeoffs, and following on material procurement

Aug 2018 – Feb 2020 Procurement Engineer Consolidated Contractors Company

Khazzan Central Processing Facility Phase II, Sultanate of Oman

- Worked on the procurement of permanent material and site consumables including sending requests for quotation, preparing comparison sheets, issuing purchase orders, and following delivery to site
- Coordinated with specialized subcontractors for timely delivery of material and mobilization of manpower
- Worked with engineering department for preparing material takeoffs for E&I

Mohamad Rabbani

Electrical & Computer Engineer





+7 705 203 5486



mohamadrabbani

Jan 2017 – Jul 2018 E&I Engineer Consolidate Contractors Company

Rabab Harweel Integrated Project, Sultanate of Oman

- Supervising construction activities including installation of switchgear, cabling, building service systems and general electrical works
- Overseeing project specification, identifying work scope and responsibility matrix, preparing method statements and material approvals
- Preparing material takeoffs and following on material procurement
- Liaising with subcontractors for supply of material and manpower to complete specific jobs
- Preparing progress and productivity reports, managing office documentation and subsystem handover

May 2015 – Dec 2016 E&I Engineer Consolidate Contractors Company

Khazzan Central Processing Facility Phase I, Sultanate of Oman

- Supervising construction activities in substations and field to install electrical equipment including HV and LV switchgear, transformers and busducts, UPS system, building HVAC, cable tray and cabling, instrument process control, F&G, and Telecoms
- Leading team to ensure proper execution of work as per drawings, project standards and quality requirements
- Coordinating with other disciplines to ensure readiness of site and complete delivery of work
- Setting delivery schedules, allocating manpower and resources, monitoring work progress and productivity
- Attending client meetings to acquire requisites, report progress and meet mechanical completion requirements

Education

Sep 2010 – Jun 2014 BS in Electrical and Computer Engineering

American University of Beirut, Beirut, Lebanon

- Attended courses in industrial electrification, control systems, electronics and signal processing, programing, software engineering, networking, and communications
- Delivered graduation project on signal interference detection and elimination in GSM systems

Jun 2013 – Aug 2013 Research Assistant (Software developer)

University of Wisconsin at Madison, USA

 Updated software packages and developed testing tools that ensure robust and reliable output